simplehelix.com 2014-12-21

# Policies | Company | Simple Helix

## Terms of Service

We will never sell, distribute, reveal, or make available of any customer information.We support the work of the anti-spam organizations. If there is ever a need to contact you in regards to your specific account and service, we will only contact you though email. We reserve the right to make any reasonable adjustments to our terms of service at anytime. Clients agree to abide by any additions or adjustments to our terms of service, as they are available to be viewed by anyone at anytime.

### Satisfaction Guaranteed

For Shared Accounts ONLY: If for any legitimate reason you are unsatisfied with our services during the first 30 days, you may request to discontinue our services and receive your full refund by emailing us at [sales@simplehelix.com](mailto:support@simplehelix.com). You must provide us with a reason as to why you are choosing to cancel our services. We are the sole arbiter in determining the validity of your reason. If all possible steps were taken on your side and on ours to correct the situation a full refund will be issued. This guarantee only applies to the first 30 days and does not apply to any accounts other than shared.

### Domain Names and Domain Transfers

As part of our "ethical hosting guidelines", we will take necessary steps to register domain names on behalf of the client when requested. However, clients are responsible for renewing their domain names. We do not take responsibility for failing to renew domain names. If your domain name was registered via our company, you must check and take appropriate actions to renew a domain that is about to expire. We do not handle renewals unless specifically asked for by sending a ticket to our help desk. If you have any questions at all about DNS changes or domain names in general, please email [ support@simplehelix.com](mailto:support@simplehelix.com).

### Payments

All invoices will be generated and sent out 7 days before they are due. All clients will receive a reminder of the generated invoice 3 days before the invoice due date. Invoices will be emailed and available on the customer’s control panel to be paid. Credit Card, Check and PayPal are the three forms of payment accepted 3 days after the invoice is due you will receive an overdue reminder. If payment is not received within 48 hours of the overdue reminder the account will be suspended until payment is made. After 30 days from time of suspension, the account will be terminated and remaining invoice balance will be sent to collections.

3 days after the invoice is due you will receive an overdue reminder. If payment is not received within 48 hours of the overdue reminder the account will be suspended until payment is made. After 30 days from time of suspension, the account will be terminated and remaining invoice balance will be sent to collection.

Please be advised that by selecting the yellow PayPal "Pay Now" or "Subscribe" button, a recurring PayPal subscription will be initiated. PayPal is a third party payment gateway, and as a result, clients are solely responsible for the creation, maintenance, and cancellation of any recurring subscriptions. We do not have the ability to initiate or cancel a PayPal subscription on behalf of our clients. Therefore, it is the responsibility of the client to cancel PayPal subscriptions along with any of our services to prevent continuous billing through PayPal. All approved PayPal refunds will be issued via paper check. In an instance a duplicate PayPal subscription is created, we will either issue account or credit or issue a refund check for the duplicate PayPal payment. For questions regarding your PayPal payments, please contact our [Billing Department](https://manage.simplehelix.com/submitticket.php?step=2&deptid=3).

We reserve the right to update product and service pricing at any time. We will endeavor to give you 30 days in advance of any hosting plan price changes, and seven days in advance of any "add on" service price changes. Clients will be notified of said changes via support ticket opened on the client's behalf by us.

### Affiliates Program

Affiliate Program members may choose to withdraw their affiliate earnings to be applied as client account credit. Members may also choose to be paid by check to be mailed to the specified physical address of the affiliate member. Clients wishing to receive their affiliate earnings via check agree to complete and submit a W9 before payout will be processed. Affiliate withdrawals can only be made in the minimum withdrawal amount of $100.00. Affiliate withdrawal payouts will be processed at the end of each month upon receipt of an affiliate withdrawal request. To submit your affiliate withdrawal request, please [submit a support ticket](https://manage.simplehelix.com/submitticket.php?step=2&deptid=7).

### Cancellations

We want to be sure we've done everything we can to make your experience is a great one, so if you do want to cancel your account with us, we ask you to call us to do so.  This way we can handle your request and, if applicable, take any input you'd like to give us to improve service for our customers.   To cancel a service, please follow the instructions below:

\- US Customers: Please call our Billing Department at 866-963-0424.    
\- UK Customers: Please call our Billing Department at 0-808-189-3147.   
\- International Customers: Please provide the information below via our cancellation form regarding your request for cancellation.  
    \- Cancellation Type: Immediate or End of Billing Cycle.  
    \- Reason for Cancellation.   

Please note that our billing department is available Monday through Friday from 8:00 AM to 5:00 PM CST.

**NOTE: IT MAY TAKE UP TO SEVENTY-TWO (72) HOURS FOR THE CANCELLATION REQUEST TO BE FULLY PROCESSED.**  
Costs and fees do not continue to accumulate after we receive the cancellation notice, but there are no pro-rated credits or refunds if the cancellation notice is received after the renewal date of the services in question (see Refunds/Account Termination below).

If you wish to cancel your services, you must call us (or, for international customers, file your request via our cancellation form) no less than eight days prior to your renewal date. If you give us notice of cancellation of your services between eight and one day prior to your service renewal, you will also need to submit a support ticket to ensure billing of these services does not continue. Services canceled after the renewal date are not eligible for a refund. If you cancel your account and your payments still continue for any reasons such as 1) by fault of our staff 2) by fault of the credit card processor 3) by fault of any other payment collection company we are not responsible for any overdraft fees that are issued by your financial institution.

### Overage Charges

Our hosting plans are designed to accommodate the majority of usage scenarios given the needs of our customers. However, your usage may vary and require additional allocations, specifically in the areas of storage and traffic. We will never charge your card automatically if your account requires more resources. You must keep your email address updated within your Control Panel (cPanel), so that you may receive an email when your account reaches certain limits determined solely by our system. You will receive a bandwidth exceedment warning at 80% at which time you may contact us to purchase a higher transfer quota for your account. Clients with overages will be charged $1.00 per GB of overage to be automatically invoiced on your service renewal date. If you chose to upgrade your plan to accommodate your usage, this fee may be waived.

### Refunds/Account Termination

If, for any reason, we fail to deliver said services, a prorated credit can be issued upon request. No credits will be issued if your account was suspended or terminated for abuse of our stated policies. In the event you request account cancellation, once your service has been cancelled your account will be suspended from use. It will then be deleted within 30 days.

Cancellations of accounts pre-paid for on a monthly basis will not receive a credit/refund for the remainder of the billing period, therefore we encourage to only submit cancellation when the account will no longer be used. Cancellations of accounts pre-paid on a yearly basis will only receive a pro-rated credit, not a refund, based on the monthly rate of the same hosting plan, where any applicable credits will be issued to the client account and can be used to purchase other services/products by client at anytime. All add-on service payments are non-refundable as they are included only during the life of the hosting plan. If for any other reason your account becomes suspended and remains suspended it will be deleted after a 30-day period.

In the event your website has been suspended, cancelled or terminated for any reason, We reserve the right (but do not undertake any obligation) to retain one or more copies of the information on the web site for its own records. We further reserve the right to distribute any information on any web site to the information's owner of record, upon said owner providing adequate proof of ownership as determined in our sole discretion. You specifically release and hold us harmless from any claims arising out of the foregoing.

### Resource Abuse

### Force Majeure

We agree to take every reasonable precaution to provide the agreed upon services to our clients. However, we will not be liable for service interruption due to circumstances beyond our control including but not limited to: natural disaster, fire, downtime caused by failure of the power grid, or downtime caused by government acquisition or seizure of our assets.

### Suspensions

In the event your website has been suspended for resource abuse (abuse that cannot be resolved by removing/changing a script, etc.) and you do not wish to upgrade to a dedicated server to accommodate your site’s needs, we will only release the suspension after a period of not less than 24-48 hours. This is to ensure the CPU intensive site slows down in traffic to avoid further damage and problems. A backup will then be provided of your files or you will be allowed FTP/cPanel access for a certain time period.

In the event your website is suspended due to non-payment, the site will not be unsuspended until payment has been received and applied to all overdue invoices. Clients have the ability to pay, add funds, and apply those funds to any outstanding invoices through their client area. Services will be unsuspended within 24 hours upon receipt of payment. 

### Restorations

In the event that any, or all information on your site is inadvertently removed, we will attempt to provide a restore from our backups for a $25.00 fee. If files have been inadvertently removed due to a fault on the part of our staff, a restore will be provided free of charge at our reasonable discretion.

## Acceptable Use Policy

We do not routinely monitor the activity of services used by customer for violation of this Acceptable Use Policy (the “Policy”). However, in our efforts to promote good citizenship within the Internet community, we will respond appropriately if we become aware of inappropriate use of our Services. Although we have no obligation to monitor Services provided and/or the network, we, and various of our affiliates and partners reserve the right to monitor bandwidth, usage, and content from time to time to operate our Services; to identify violations of this Policy; and/or to protect the network and our customers. In other words, we reserve the right (but shall have no obligation) to pre-screen, review, flag, filter, modify, refuse or remove any or all content from any Service for any reason.

**Prohibited Actions under the Acceptable Use Policy include, but are not limited to:**

Objectionable Content- Any content (written, visual, or implied) that:

  * infringes upon any copyright, trademark, trade secret, or patent of any third party;
  * violates any obligation of confidentiality;
  * violates the privacy, publicity, moral or any other right of any third party;
  * is hateful or obscene;
  * is being used to harass, stalk, or otherwise threaten a person;
  * is libelous, defamatory, knowingly false or misrepresents another person or;
  * is threatening, promotes violence, promotes discrimination (whether based on sex, religion, race, ethnicity, nationality, disability or age), promotes illegal activities or otherwise contains materials that we inform you that we consider objectionable. 

### Impersonation/Forgery:

  * Adding, removing, or modifying identifying network header information (aka “spoofing”) in an effort to deceive or mislead.
  * Attempting to impersonate any person by using forged headers or other identifying information.

### Network unfriendly activity:

  * Any activities which adversely affect the ability of other people or systems to use Simple Helix services or the Internet are prohibited. This includes “denial of service” attacks against the Simple Helix servers, network hosts or individual user.

### Commercial Email

  * Sending unsolicited commercial e-mail. Using one of our products or services to distribute unsolicited commercial e-mail is prohibited.
  * Sending large volumes of unsolicited e-mail (aka “mail bombing”) is prohibited.

### Access control and Authentication

  * Attempting to circumvent user authentication or security of any host, network, or account (aka “cracking”). This includes, but is not limited to, accessing data not intended for the customer, logging into a server or account the customer is not expressly authorized to access, or probing the security of Simple Helix servers and networks.

### Proxy Hunters, Spiders, Robots:

  * Using any program/script/command, or sending messages of any kind, designed to interfere with a User’s session, by any means, locally or by the internet.

We prefer that you self-govern your content and remain responsible and all-knowing of your website publicly provides. Even if other users have access to your account, you are responsible for their actions. If we are made aware of any questionable content on site hosted by us, we will address the concerns immediately and directly with you to seek a resolution. If any person contacts us about content they have found on our server that copyrights their own material or that they wish to be removed, we require a proper DMCA notice to begin investigation.

We believe in the freedom of speech and prefer to advise customers of inappropriate behavior and have the customer undertake any necessary corrective action. However, if our Services are used in a way that we or our distribution affiliates, in our reasonable discretion, believe violate this Policy, we, or our distribution affiliates, may take any responsive actions deemed appropriate. Such actions include, but are not limited to, temporary or permanent removal of content, cancellation of newsgroup posts, filtering of Internet transmissions, and the immediate suspension or termination of all or any portion of Services provided by us. Neither us nor our distribution affiliates will have any liability for any such responsive actions. The above-described actions are not our exclusive remedies and we may take any other legal or technical action it deems appropriate.

We reserve the right to investigate suspected violations of this Policy, including the gathering of information from the user or users involved and the complaining party, if any, and examination of material on our servers and network. During an investigation, we may suspend the service or services of the customer involved and/or remove material which potentially violates this Policy. You hereby authorize us and our distribution affiliates to cooperate with (i) law enforcement authorities in the investigation of suspected criminal violations, and (ii) and system administrators at other Internet service providers or other network or computing facilities in order to enforce this Policy. Such cooperation may include us providing the name, IP address(es), or other identifying information about a customer. Upon termination of a customer’s service, we are authorized to delete any files, programs, data and email messages associated with such account.

You agree that you are solely responsible for (and that we have no responsibility to you or to any third party for) any content that you create, transmit, or display while using any goods or services provided by us and that you are solely responsible for the consequences of your actions (including any loss or damage which we may suffer) by doing so.

Any failure by us or our distribution affiliates to enforce this Policy, for whatever reason, will not be construed as a waiver of any right to do so at any time. You agree that, if any portion of this Policy is held invalid or unenforceable, that portion will be construed consistent with applicable law as nearly as possible, and the remaining portions will remain in full force and effect. This Policy shall be exclusively governed by, and construed in accordance with, the laws of the State of Alabama.

## Privacy Policy

We don’t sell your info, we don’t spam you, we don’t sell your personal info to spammers. We use a 3rd party credit card processor, so we don’t even keep credit cards on file. We use a variety of data security measures intended to ensure the confidentiality and integrity of your personal information. Your personal information is as safe with us as it’s likely to be just about anywhere. If we send you email, it’ll be because it pertains to your account with us, not to try and sell you something or solicit you for something.

You should know that personal data that either we or our affiliates (collectively, “we” or “us”) may collect may be transferred to other affiliates and subsidiaries, and, under limited circumstances, to platform partners (as more fully described below) where it is necessary to meet the purpose for which the visitor has submitted the information. By submitting data on our web sites, the visitor is providing explicit consent to transmission of data collected on the web sites for the fulfillment of their voluntary requests.

Please remember that no computer system should be considered safe from intrusion. E-mail may pass through many computer systems, and should not be considered a secure means of communication unless encrypted. Even then, information is only as secure as the encryption method. Therefore, although we take many precautions to protect our system and our servers, we cannot guarantee the security of any data on any server, including “secure servers.”

### Data Collection

We are sensitive to protecting the private information that our customers and visitors provide to us. We want you to have the opportunity to obtain interesting and useful information, products and services through us and our affiliates. The loyalty of our customers is very important to us and we hope this policy will underscore our commitment to making sure your experience with us is a good one. This Privacy Policy describes how we treat information received about you when you become a customer; under what conditions this information may be shared or released to another party; cookies; other sites; how material revisions to the policy will be conveyed; and contact information. Please read the Privacy Policy carefully.

### Information Collection and Use

Personal information regarding your name, company, address, etc., may be requested. This information is usually gathered in order to fulfill information requests from you, deliver products and services, and enable you to participate in our online discussion group.

We do not collect personal information about you when you visit our website unless you choose to provide that information to us. We collect limited non-personally identifying information your browser makes available automatically whenever you visit a website. This information may include the Internet Address of your computer or network, the date, time, and page you visited on our site, your browser and operating system, and the referring page. We may use the aggregated information from all of our visitors to measure server performance, analyze user traffic patterns and improve the content of our site.

### Collection of Customer Information

Some of our online services require you to register for an account or become a customer. Customer information is information such as name, address, telephone number, and credit card information — information that identifies a particular individual or business. We collect and stores customer information in the following ways: As part of a customer’s registration for our services, customers must provide their user name, address, telephone number(s), company name (if applicable), and credit card or other billing information. We confirm your requested e-mail address(es) or domain registration(s) or Web site(s). Depending on the service(s) you select, we will give you a user ID number and one or more passwords that you must use to access and receive the services. We retain this information in our customer databases. If you purchase other goods or services from us through our web site, we will also collect your billing information. Any financial information that we collect is used solely to bill you for products and services that you have ordered.

### Example of How We Use Customer Information For Billing

  * To examine system accounting logs, user mailboxes and other company records to resolve e-mail and other system errors or problems; to make sure that only our customers are able to access certain member-only services. This information is kept on limited access computers and is only available to those employees who have a need to know.
  * We provide some information to companies that we use to perform certain functions for us — for example, credit card numbers are sent to a credit card processing company for billing, and address information is given to a fulfillment company that sends out our software starter kits. These companies are authorized to use this information only for the expressed purpose of completing our business and are not authorized to release this information to other third parties.
  * Occasionally, we use our customer database to distribute newsletters or important notices to our customers. We may also use customer information to enforce our Appropriate Use Policy as described in the User’s Guide, but only to the extent necessary.
  * We will share customer information with governmental authorities when legally required to do so, and may cooperate with these authorities investigating claims of illegal activity such as (but not limited to) illegal transfer or use of copyrighted material, or postings or e-mail containing threats of violence. Except under the limited circumstances described above, we do not disclose customer information to third parties.

### Voluntary Customer Surveys 

If you have been with us for a while, you most likely know that we periodically conduct both business and individual customer surveys. We encourage all of our customers to participate in these surveys because they provide us with important information that helps us to improve the types of services we offer and how we provide them to you. Your personal information and responses will remain strictly confidential, even if the survey is conducted by a third party. Please remember that your participation in our customer surveys is voluntary.

### How We Use Customer Survey Responses

We take the information we receive from individuals responding to our Customer Surveys and combine (or aggregate) it with the responses of other customers to create broader, generic responses to the survey questions (such as gender, age, residence, hobbies, education, employment, industry sector or other demographic information). We then use the aggregated information to improve the quality of our services to you, and to develop new services and products. The aggregated information may be shared with third parties.

### Website Use and Navigation Information

Each time a user visits our web site, certain anonymous use and navigation information is collected by our servers. This information is aggregated and anonymous. It tell us how our Web Site is used and navigated, including the number, frequency and duration of visits to each web page. Web site use and navigation information that we collect may include the domain names of visitors who are not already our customers (such as “www.user’sinternet-service-provider.com”), and of our customers, but it does not otherwise contain individually identifiable information about any visitor to our Web Site.

### How We Use Website Use and Navigation Information

Like customer survey information, we use the anonymous, aggregated information to improve the content and navigation features of our Web Site. We also may use the anonymous, aggregated information to enable our affiliates or advertisers to evaluate whether to post advertising banners or other material on our web site.

### Platform Partners

We have relationships with certain service providers (our “platform partners”) for services that may be of interest to you. These services include things like web site design, development and consultation. If you elect to use a platform provided by a platform partner, we will share certain information with that partner.

### How and What We Disclose to Platform Partners

As noted above, if you choose to use a particular third party platform, we will share certain information with that platform provider. In other words, choosing to use a particular platform is your consent for us to share information about you with the platform partner. The information we share may include your name, address, telephone number(s), company name (if applicable) and email address. We share this information for the limited purpose of customer relationship management.

### Information Sharing and Disclosure

We gather and track this information for our internal use and does not sell or disclose personal information without your prior permission, including email addresses, to third parties, partners, or affiliates except for the limited purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy (e.g., third party billings, and voluntary surveys and platform partner services that you use). We will only utilize the information provided to us in the manner described herein. Your email addresses are not for sale or trade and are strictly guarded. Our Terms of Services agreement prohibits our customers from sending unsolicited bulk commercial email (aka "spam") using our services. If it is brought to our attention that one of our customers is violating this policy, we take steps to stop them and ensure it doesn't happen again.

### Cookies

Like most web sites, we make use of browser “cookies”. Cookies are files written to a user’s hard disk and read by server programs to inform a web site if the user has previously visited that site. We use cookies to continually enhance your experience with is, and may use them in the future to store customer preferences and choices. Our Account Management web pages use cookies to store and retrieve session identifiers that correspond to a secure database containing each customer’s user name and password information. This is designed to facilitate access by customers to member services. Customers cannot access the Account Management web pages unless they have a browser that supports these cookies. These cookies do not enable third parties to access any of your customer information. Companies who advertise on our web site may also use cookie technology. We do not control the use of cookies by our advertisers.

### Other Sites

This Privacy Policy applies solely to the information collection practice on our web site. From time to time, we may include links to other sites on our web site. Please be aware that we have no control or influence over the privacy practices of such other sites. When you link to another website, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our web site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that they visit.

### Cross-Border Transfer of Personal Information

Your personal information may be transferred to other countries for processing, and by using our services, you consent to the transfer of information to countries outside of your country of residence, which may have different personal data protection rules than in your country. Simple Helix, LLC and certain of its affiliates participate in the U.S. Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor principles for the transfer of personal data. Please visit our Safe Harbor Privacy Policy <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/> to learn more.

### Policy Changes

Please note this Privacy Policy can change from time to time. We expect most such changes to be minor, but we will post those changes as they occur. The effective date of the changes will be represented by the Effective Date posted on the bottom of this page. We may also decide to notify our customers by e-mail of significant changes.

### Questions/Requests

Simple Helix welcomes any questions regarding this Privacy Policy or requests for changes to any personally identifiable information. Please contact us at Attn: Privacy Policy Questions 4092 Memorial Pkwy., Ste. 202, Huntsville, Alabama 35802; or call 866-963-0424.

### Effective Date: May 8, 2014

## Liability Limitations

Simple Helix, LLC, and it parent company, affiliates, subsidiaries or designees nor each of their respective officers, directors, employees, agents, third-party content providers, designers, contractors, distributors, merchants, sponsors, licensors or the like (collectively, “Simple Helix”) make no endorsement, claims, or promises regarding the services offered by our customers and will not be held liable for any disputes or claims against said customers. In no event shall Simple Helix, be liable for any direct, indirect, incidental, consequential, special and exemplary damages, or any damages whatsoever, arising from the use or performance of a customer web site or from any information, services or products provided through a customer web site. If there is questionable content on any server in our network, we will not take any action against any material or action until the website is brought to our attention by emailing our abuse department at [abuse@simplehelix.com](mailto:abuse@simplehelix.com).

By using any product or service offered by Simple Helix, you expressly agree that use of such product or service is at your sole risk. Express as expressly provided to the contrary, the products and services offered by Simple Helix are provided on an "AS IS" and "as available" basis. Simple Helix does not warrant the accuracy, integrity, or completeness of the products or services offered by Simple Helix. Further, Simple Helix makes no representation that products and services provided on are applicable to, or appropriate for use in, locations outside of the United States. Simple Helix specifically disclaims all warranties, whether expressed or implied, including but not limited to warranties of title, merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose, except as specifically and expressly provided to the contrary. No oral advice or written information given by Simple Helix will create a warranty. Some states do not allow the exclusion or limitation of certain warranties, so the above limitation or exclusion may not apply to you.

Under no circumstances will Simple Helix be liable for any direct, indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages that result from your use of or inability to use the products and services of Simple Helix, including but not limited to reliance by you on any information obtained from Simple Helix that results in mistakes, omissions, interruptions, deletion or corruption of files, viruses, delays in operation or transmission, unauthorized intrusions or any failure of performance. The foregoing Limitation of Liability shall apply in any action, whether in contract, tort or any other claim, even if an authorized representative of Simple Helix has been advised of or should have knowledge of the possibility of such damages. User hereby acknowledges that this paragraph shall apply to all content, merchandise, and services available through Simple Helix. Some states do not allow the exclusion of limitation of incidental or consequential damages, so the above limitation or exclusion may not apply to you.

ANY MATERIAL DOWNLOADED OR OTHERWISE OBTAINED THROUGH THE USE OF THE SERVICES IS DONE AT YOUR OWN DISCRETION AND RISK AND YOU WILL BE SOLELY RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY DAMAGE TO YOUR COMPUTER SYSTEM OR OTHER DEVICE OR LOSS OF DATA THAT RESULTS FROM ANY SUCH MATERIAL.

IN NO EVENT WILL THE LIABILITY OF SIMPLE HELIX FOR ANY CLAIM UNDER ANY THEORY WHATSOEVER EXCEED ANY AMOUNTS IN EXCESS OF THE TOTAL FEES PAID TO SIMPLE HELIX FOR SERVICE OR EQUIPMENT DURING THE SIX (6)-MONTH PERIOD IMMEDIATELY PRECEDING THE OCCURRENCE GIVING RISE TO ALLEGED LIABILITY.

### Indemnification

You will defend, indemnify, and hold harmless Simple Helix from and against any and all claims, demands, actions, causes of action, judgments, liabilities, damages, losses, injuries, costs and expenses arising from (a) the use or misuse of the Service or Equipment by you or by any person you allow to use the Service or Equipment, or (b) any breach of these Terms by you, including, but not limited to, claims by any owner of the primary location where you use the Service and claims by or through any customers you may have. You also agree to pay Simple Helix's reasonable attorneys' fees and costs related to prosecuting or defending such claims and to enforcing these Terms, including any and all such fees incurred in connection with any appeal. The rights and responsibilities established in this paragraph will survive any termination of this Agreement.

## Scope of Support

We understand that the technical support you receive from your web hosting provider is just as important as the service we deliver. We're pleased to provide our customers with access to our "in house", 24/7 Technical Support Team through our [support ticket system](https://manage.simplehelix.com/submitticket.php). Due to the nature of web hosting, there are certain aspects of your site that we cannot manage or support on your behalf for reasons of liability. For your convenience, we've provided the following document to outline what aspects of your website and hosting services our highly capable staff can assist you with.

### We Support/Our Services:

### Hardware

If you're on our shared servers, or on one of our managed dedicated servers, then you can rest assured that we are stringently monitoring your server day and night with protective measures in place and ready to go in the unlikely event that hardware failure should occur.

### Server Software

We maintain, update, and secure all software on our servers such as PHP, Apache, and MySQL. While we make every attempt to keep our software "up to date", we cannot guarantee that each server will always have the most recent version of all software installed.

### DNS Zone Files

For clients using our DNS, we've got you covered by providing you with a DNS zone file adequate for typical hosting usage.

### Basic Services

We know what our clients want and need, and we gladly support basic email function, web service, trouble shooting within your control panel, basic FTP and upon request we can enable SSH. We frequently monitor all of these services to ensure that they are working and functioning up to our high standards.

### Basic Magento Queries

Being a Magento-specific hosting company, the large majority of support inquiries we receive are Magento-related. Our Tech Support Team is fully capable of assisting you with Magento installation and initial setup/configuration inquiries. We also provide support for Magento upgrades. Just keep in mind that each upgrade is as new to our staff as it is to you, and as is often the case with any upgrade, we won't be able to identify any "bugs" or "quirks" right off the bat. Our Tech Support Team generally recommends holding off on upgrades until about two weeks after their release. (That way, other people get to work out the "kinks" and we get the benefit of the knowledge, without having to suffer through any of the initial "discovery".)

### Our Clients Support:

### Basic Foundation

When signing up for services, we assume that our clients have at least a sub structural understanding of the web hosting basics (email, FTP, DNS...etc). For our clients needing assistance in this area, we do provide basic tutorials for both control panels. You can view them [here](http://www.simplehelix.com/support/video-tutorials).

### Domain Names

We do not have the ability to update nameservers or contact information of domain names that are not in our control. If you are not using our nameservers, we cannot adjust your DNS records. On a similar note, our clients are responsible for ensuring that their domain names transfer successfully to our system. Upon your request, we can investigate the status of a domain name transfer and even re-initiate the transfer if necessary. For answers to questions about your domain name transfer, visit our [knowledgebase](https://manage.simplehelix.com/knowledgebase.php).

### FTP and Email Client Configuration

As we do not configure your FTP or Email clients, we do not have the ability to support your advanced FTP or Email client configurations. We may be able to offer advice regarding your setup, however, any suggestion offered by our staff is to be implemented at the client's discretion. We will not accept responsibility for the outcome of any instruction offered outside of our Scope of Support.

### Scripts and Applications

We cannot provide support for your customized script or application. We may be able to provide suggestions or support for some common applications, though there may be an additional charge associated with such support. Not to worry, we will notify you of any support related charges before proceeding with the requested support.

### Site Content

While our staff can ensure that FTP and your control panel are functioning properly, our clients are responsible for adding and editing site content. This includes, but is not limited to: adding images, removing images, uploading video, editing HMTL, or programming.

### Magento Store Content

Just as we don't support site content, we staff cannot alter your Magento store content. This includes but is not limited to: adding products, removing products, Magento store design, and editing product descriptions, templates or themes, payment gateways,and extensions.

## Service-Level Agreement (SLA)

This Service Level Agreement between you and Simple Helix, LLC ("Simple Helix") (the “SLA”) covers three components that support the availability of your web site:

1\. Network Infrastructure

2\. Data Center Infrastructure

3\. Server Hardware

### 1\. Network Infrastructure

We guarantee that our data center network infrastructure will be available 100% of the time (as measured on a monthly basis), excluding scheduled or emergency maintenance. The data center network means the portion of our network extending from the outbound port on your edge device to the outbound port of the data center border router.

Should our network infrastructure become unavailable for a cumulative period up to 20 minutes beyond the 100% minimum in any month of service, the client can receive a credit equivalent to 5% of the client's recurring monthly fees up to 100% of your monthly fee for the affected server(s). In no event will credit accumulated during any monthly billing period exceed 100% of one monthly billing fee.

### 2\. Data Center Infrastructure

We guarantee that data center HVAC and power (including UPSs, PDUs and cabling) will be available 100% of the time (as measured on a monthly basis), excluding scheduled or emergency maintenance. Data center infrastructure power does not include the power supplies on your server hardware. Should our data center infrastructure become unavailable for a cumulative period up to 20 minutes beyond the 100% minimum in any month of service, the client can receive a credit equivalent to 5% of the client's recurring monthly fees up to 100% of your monthly fee for the affected server(s). In no event will credit accumulated during any monthly billing period exceed 100% of one monthly billing fee. 

### 3\. Server Hardware

We guarantee 100% functioning of all server hardware components and will replace any failed component at no cost. "Server Hardware" means the processor(s), RAM, hard disk(s), motherboard, NIC card and other related hardware included with the server. Server hardware replacement will begin once we identify the cause of the problem and will be complete within one hour of problem identification.

Once server hardware has been identify as faulty, the client can receive a credit equivalent to 5% of the client's recurring monthly fees up to 100% of your monthly fee per additional hour of downtime for the affected server(s). In no event will credit accumulated during any monthly billing period exceed 100% of one monthly billing fee.

**Credit Request** \- All credit calculations will be based on unavailability in 20-minute increments unless credit is related to a server hardware guarantee, which will be calculated in hourly increments. Any and all credits to the client will not exceed 100% of the client's recurring monthly fees for the month in which the credit is paid. All SLA credits must be requested within 15 days of the incident via the client area. A failure to request credit within 15 days of the incident operates as a waiver to the right to any credit.

## Safe Harbor Agreement

Simple Helix, LLC and its affiliate, Alpha Hosting, LLC (collectively, “Simple Helix”) complies with the US-EU Safe Harbor Framework and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Simple Helix has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.

### About the Safe Harbor

The “U.S.-EU Safe Harbor” program was established cooperatively by the United States Department of Commerce and the European Commission in 2000. This program sets forth the principles for the transfer of personal information from the European Union (“EU”) to companies operating in the United States. The “U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor” program was established cooperatively by the United States Department of Commerce and the Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner of Switzerland in 2009. This program sets forth the principles for the transfer of personal information from Switzerland to companies operating in the United States.

Participation in the Safe Harbor programs is voluntary for companies operating in the United States. Companies participating in the Safe Harbor programs annually self-certify compliance with privacy standards adopted by the EU Commission and Switzerland and the United States Department of Commerce.

### Scope

This Safe Harbor Statement governs personal information transferred from countries in the EU and Switzerland to the United States and in connection with Simple Helix business activities.

For the purpose of Safe Harbor, “personal information” shall mean any information which may, directly or indirectly, identify or lead to the identification of a person. Personal information shall include, but is not limited to, an individual’s name, address, email address, telephone number, government identification number, license numbers of any kind, or photographs. Personal information shall not include information that is anonymous, stripped of identifying details, encoded or encrypted, or aggregated. Personal information also shall not include any information that is publicly available, except where such public information is supplemented with non-public, personally identifying information.

### Safe Harbor Privacy Principles

The following principles form the core of the Safe Harbor programs:

### Notice

Any personal information received by Simple Helix in connection with its business is provided voluntarily by persons having “ownership” of such information. Simple Helix provides persons with an explanation about the types of information collected or maintained, how such information is maintained and protected, and how to contact Simple Helix to request review, correction or deletion of such information. Personal information is never disclosed to a third party without consent of the affected individual(s).

Simple Helix also maintains a Privacy Statement on its corporate websites which outlines the collection and use of any information collected from persons visiting such websites.

In certain limited cases and only where authorized by Safe Harbor principles, Simple Helix may be unable to provide notice of disclosure of personal information to affected person(s). For example, Safe Harbor principles do not require notice where disclosure of personal information is required to comply with a court or other valid government order or inquiry, where applicable laws or regulations waive notice requirements, or where protection of legitimate Simple Helix legal interests would be compromised by notice.

### Choice

Simple Helix will not use any personal information collected from or about covered individuals for any purpose not authorized by the individual. For the purpose of this section, voluntary provision of personal information in connection with the performance of certain activities will constitute authorization as will a written statement granting permission to use or disclose information for certain stated purposes. Individuals may contact Simple Helix at any time to inquire about the types of personal information Simple Helix currently maintains and to request either changes in authorized uses or deletion of their personal information from Simple Helix records.

### Data Integrity

Simple Helix strives to ensure that any personal information collected or maintained about covered individuals is complete, accurate and reliable for the purposes for which the information was obtained or authorized.

### Transfers to Third Parties

Simple Helix does not share personal information collected with any third parties without consent.

### Access and Correction

Covered individuals may contact Simple Helix in writing to request reasonable access to their personal information. Simple Helix will take reasonable steps to allow such individuals to review, correct or request deletion of their personal information.

### Security 

Simple Helix has implemented a variety commercially reasonable physical security and information technology measures to protect personal information. Such security measures are supplemented by operational procedures and staff training.

### Enforcement 

Simple Helix has established internal management practices and policies to support the Safe harbor principles. Simple Helix encourages covered individuals with concerns about its information management practices to contact Simple Helix at the address below.

### Dispute Resolution

Any questions or concerns regarding the use or disclosure of personal information should be directed to Simple Helix as follows:

**By post:**

Attn: Dispute Resolution Department

4092 Memorial Pkwy. SW

Ste. 202

Huntsville, Alabama 35802

**By facsimile:**

Attn: Dispute Resolution Department

866-963-0423

**By email:**

Simple Helix will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of personal information by reference to the principles contained in this Policy. For complaints that cannot be resolved between Simple Helix and the complainant, Simple Helix has agreed to participate in the following dispute resolution procedures in the investigation and resolution of complaints to resolve disputes pursuant to the Safe Harbor Principles:

1\. For disputes involving any personal information received by Simple Helix from Switzerland, Simple Helix has agreed and to cooperate and comply with the Swiss FDPIC,

2\. For disputes involving any personal information received by Simple Helix from the European Economic Area (“EEA”), Simple Helix has agreed to cooperate and comply with the data protection authorities in the EEA and to participate in the dispute resolution procedures of the panel established by the European data protection authorities.

### OR: 

Simple Helix has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by Simple Helix, please visit the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR web site at [http://www.bbb.org/council/eusafeharbor/bbb-eu-safe-harbor-dispute-resolution-program/how-to-file-a-complaint-with-bbb-eu-safe-harbor/ ](http://www.bbb.org/council/eusafeharbor/bbb-eu-safe-harbor-dispute-resolution-program/how-to-file-a-complaint-with-bbb-eu-safe-harbor/) for more information and to file a complaint.

### Limitation on Scope of Principles

Simple Helix will take all reasonable steps to comply with Safe Harbor principles and this policy. Strict compliance with Safe Harbor or these policies may be limited in certain cases and as required to meet legal, governmental or national security obligations. Information about limitations is set forth in the U.S. Department of Commerce Safe Harbor website.

### Contact Information

In compliance with the US-EU Safe Harbor Principles, Simple Helix commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Simple Helix.

### Learn More

To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Simple Helix’s certification, please visit [http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/.](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/)
